import { Injectable } from '@angular/core';
import { question } from "../interfaces/question";

@Injectable({
  providedIn: 'root'
})
export class GameService {

  currentQuestion = 0;
  constructor() { }

  startNewGame(){
    this.currentQuestion = 0;
    this.setQuestions("the type of questions to get");
  }

  setQuestions(type:string){
    // this.questions =
  }


  // mock data
  questions: question[] = [
    {
      exercise: "Find the sum of 9+10",
      answer: "21",
      wrongAnswers: ["19","20","91"],
      help:"test Text",
      difficultyType:"Easy",
      categoryType: "Analysis",
      time: 2000,
      multipleChoiceAnswers: [
        "19",
        "20",
        "21",
        "91"
      ]
    },
    //
    // {
    //   question: "Find the sum of 111+222+333",
    //   answer: "666",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "700",
    //     "666",
    //     "10",
    //     "100"
    //   ]
    // },
    //
    // {
    //   question: "Subtract 457 from 832",
    //   answer: "375",
    //   time: 15,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "375",
    //     "57",
    //     "376",
    //     "970"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "50 times 5 is equal to",
    //   answer: "None of these",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "2500",
    //     "505",
    //     "500",
    //     "None of these"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Find the product of 72 × 3",
    //   answer: "216",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "216",
    //     "7230",
    //     "106",
    //     "372"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Solve 200 – (96 ÷ 4)",
    //   answer: "176",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "105",
    //     "176",
    //     "26",
    //     "16"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Simplify : 3 + 6 x (5 + 4) ÷ 3 - 7",
    //   answer: "14",
    //   time: 15,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "11",
    //     "16",
    //     "14",
    //     "15"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Find x : x + 10 = 0",
    //   answer: "-10",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "2",
    //     "-5",
    //     "-10",
    //     "8"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Find x : x^2 - 2 = 2 ",
    //   answer: "2",
    //   time: 15,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "2",
    //     "3",
    //     "0",
    //     "4"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Find x : 5x - 11 = 3x + 9",
    //   answer: "10",
    //   time: 20,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "10",
    //     "13",
    //     "4",
    //     "None of these"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Find x : 9 - 2(x - 5) = x + 10",
    //   answer: "3",
    //   time: 25,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "2",
    //     "4",
    //     "5",
    //     "3"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Simplify : 3/4 + 1/4",
    //   answer: "1",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "1",
    //     "2",
    //     "3",
    //     "4"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Simplify : (1/8)^2 + 7/16 ",
    //   answer: "0.5",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "0.25",
    //     "0.5",
    //     "0.75",
    //     "None of these"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Simplify : 4/2 - 1/2 + 2",
    //   answer: "3.5",
    //   time: 10,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "1",
    //     "2.5",
    //     "2",
    //     "3.5"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Simplify : 2+2",
    //   answer: "4",
    //   time: 7,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "1",
    //     "2",
    //     "3",
    //     "4"
    //   ]
    // },
    // {
    //   question: "Simplify : (e^(i*pi))+2",
    //   answer: "1",
    //   time: 7,
    //   type: "multipleChoice",
    //   multipleChoiceAnswers: [
    //     "1",
    //     "0",
    //   ]
    // },
  ]

  getQuestion() : question{
    if(this.currentQuestion >= this.questions.length){
      return {
        answer: "",
        wrongAnswers: [""],
        help:"",
        difficultyType:"",
        categoryType: "",
        multipleChoiceAnswers: [
          "19",
          "20",
          "21",
          "91"
        ],
        exercise: "",
        time: 0,
        finished: true,
      }
    }else{
      return this.questions[this.currentQuestion++];
    }
  }
}
